<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>T.D.</title>
    <link>https://tdeneke.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on T.D.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Copyright 2022, Tewodros Deneke</copyright><atom:link href="https://tdeneke.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://tdeneke.github.io/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2022 20:04:38 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tdeneke.github.io/publications/</guid>
      <description>Publications   Dynamic Process Intensification via Data-Driven Dynamic Optimization: Concept and Application to Ternary Distillation, IECR, 2021.Lingqing Yan, Tewodros L. Deneke, Keijo Heljanko, Iiro Harjunkoski,Thomas F. Edgar, and Michael Baldea. 
  Synergistic and Intelligent Process Optimization – First Results and Open Challenges, IECR, 2020.Iiro Harjunkoski, Teemu Ikonen, Hossein Mostafaei, Tewodros Deneke, Keijo Heljanko. 
  Data-Driven Approach to Grade Change Scheduling Optimization in a Paper Machine, IECR, 2020.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Education</title>
      <link>https://tdeneke.github.io/education/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2022 20:13:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tdeneke.github.io/education/</guid>
      <description>Academia  Ph.D., Embedded Computing (2017)
Åbo Akademi University, FI  MSc., Embedded Computing (2012)
Åbo Akademi University, FI  BSc., Electrical Engineering (2007)
Bahir Dar University, ET   Teaching  Big Data Platforms, Main Teaching Assistant (2020)
University of Helsinki, Computer Science Department, FI  Concurrent Programming, Main Teaching Assistant (2019)
Aalto University, Computer Science Department, FI  Multimedia Algorithms and Implementation, Teaching Assistant (2013)
Åbo Akademi University, Embedded Systems Lab, FI   Trainings  Pouta Cloud: Practical Cloud Computing Course, Trainer (2021)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://tdeneke.github.io/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2022 20:04:38 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tdeneke.github.io/projects/</guid>
      <description>Projects  EOSC-Nordic: a project that aims to facilitate the coordination of European Open Science Cloud (EOSC). (2022) EOSC-Nordic, EU  Singpro: a project that aims to merge Big Data platforms, machine learning and data analytics methodologies with process planning and scheduling optimization technologies. (2020) Academy of Finland, FI  EIT BDExp: a project having as main goal the development of a viable business model for EASYTRANS, an efficient media transcoding platform.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://tdeneke.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tdeneke.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>My interests lie at the intersection between computing and data-intensive applications. I explore ways of efficiently utilizing computing platforms with specialized hardware like GPUs for deep learning, video processing, and big data analytics. Lately, I have been working with several researchers on their computing environment needs, designing, developing, and assisting them on how to efficiently utilize HPC and Cloud platforms with specialized hardware like GPUs. I have also been involved in European projects related to federated machine learning and workflow engines 1 2.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
